<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Steven Clontz]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-04T09:26:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steven Clontz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teacher Evaluations Spring 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/05/07/teacher-evaluations-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-07T12:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/05/07/teacher-evaluations-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Steven Clontz is the best professor I&#8217;ve had at Auburn thus far.</p></blockquote>

<p>Gonna brag a little. Here&#8217;s some excerpts from my student evaulation comments.</p>

<p><strong>EDIT 2013-08-06</strong> I&#8217;ve moved this sort of thing to its own page: <a href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/teaching">http://www.stevenclontz.com/teaching</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[6÷2(1+2)=?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/03/17/order-of-operations/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-17T17:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/03/17/order-of-operations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a problem that&#8217;s been thrown around the Facebook recently it seems. Man, it seems so simple:</p>

<p>$$6÷2(1+2)=?$$</p>

<p>Simple until you ask a group of people what the answer is, and find out half of us think it&#8217;s nine, and the other half think it&#8217;s one.</p>

<p>So what IS the answer?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Short answer: it&#8217;s a terribly written problem, or more accurately, it&#8217;s a problem written solely to make people argue over its order of operations. It touches on the ambiguity of parentheses, multiplication, and division in the &#8220;Please Excuse My Dear Aunt Sally / Parentheses Exponents Multiplication Division Addition Subtraction&#8221; mnemonic.</p>

<p>The issue stems from the incorrect (but often subconscious) belief that there exists a Bible of Mathematics somewhere, which decrees every detail of how arithmetic should be expressed and simplified. As simple as the problem seems, there&#8217;s no prevailing convention on whether $6÷2$ or $2(1+2)$ gets precedence here. Particularly when half of school teachers say multiplication has precedence over division, and half say multiplication and division have equal precedence and are evaluated left-to-right. (And hey does implied multiplication by parentheses fall into the P or M of PEMDAS?)</p>

<p>In the real world of mathematics, this is as unanswerable a question as me asking &#8220;Is there a mathematical size bigger than the amount of integers but less than the amount of real numbers?&#8221; <a href="#footnote-1">[1]</a> because you can&#8217;t address it without first specifying the rules you are allowed to use on the problem.</p>

<p>Thus I&#8217;m forced to settle for what we call a &#8220;consistency result&#8221;:</p>

<blockquote><p>If ÷ division takes precedence over implied multiplication located further to the right, then $6÷2(1+2)=9$. If not, then $6÷2(1+2)=1$.</p></blockquote>

<p>That&#8217;s the best that can be done, mathematically. If you wanted a definitive answer, you should have asked me to evaluate $(6÷2)(1+2)$ or $6÷(2(1+2))$. That&#8217;s what parentheses are for, anyway.</p>

<p><small id="footnote-1">[1] This is something called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuum_hypothesis">The Continuum Hypothesis</a>. We use the word &#8220;hypothesis&#8221; here because once mathematicians formalized the rules of set theory (well, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zermelo%E2%80%93Fraenkel_set_theory">one set of rules for set theory</a>), it couldn&#8217;t be proven true or false. We later proved that it <em>couldn&#8217;t</em> be proven true or false, basically because we didn&#8217;t provide enough rules to handle the question. So just like $6÷2(1+2)=9$ or $6÷2(1+2)=1$ depending on what rules we use, we can assume the answer to the Continuum Hypothesis is either yes <em>or</em> no.</p>

<p>Or we can completely ignore it and go on with our lives, just like we do with other silly questions like $6÷2(1+2)=?$.</small></p>

<p>Addendum: Someone rightfully pointed out on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5391415">Hacker News</a> that calling the Continuum Hypothesis a &#8220;silly&#8221; question doesn&#8217;t do it justice. Rather, I mean that posing the Continuum Hypothesis as a &#8220;yes or no&#8221; question is silly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Presentation for GSC Scholars' Forum 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/02/26/presentation-for-gsc-scholars-forum-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-26T19:54:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/02/26/presentation-for-gsc-scholars-forum-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I will be presenting my research tomorrow morning (2013-02-27) for the Graduate Student Council Scholars&#8217; Forum, a preliminary event for AU Research Week. It&#8217;s intended to showcase graduate student research for a general audience.</p>

<p>Hopefully I&#8217;ll do an okay job! If you&#8217;re interested in my research, I&#8217;ve made the presentation available on <a href="https://github.com/StevenClontz/2013-au-research-week-presentation/">GitHub</a> (and <a href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/aurw-2013/">added a page to my site</a>).</p>

<p>-SXC</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/nKfMSUI.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[E.T.'s March]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/02/05/e-dot-t-s-march/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-05T10:39:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/02/05/e-dot-t-s-march</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back when I was in undergrad, some friends and I decided to spend our Spring Break taking a road trip to Alamogordo, New Mexico, to make a documentary about the Atari E.T. game failure. Long story short, the game was a flop, and according to the folklore millions of copies were buried in a landfill in that city.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, lack of funds kept us from our mission. Occassionally I&#8217;ll be contacted about our attempt, and while there really isn&#8217;t much to say, I always try to contribute. The latest publication es en español, so I&#8217;ll add my original quote in English after the break.</p>

<p><a href="http://noticias.lainformacion.com/arte-cultura-y-espectaculos/videojuegos/la-tumba-de-atari-en-busca-del-tesoro-enterrado-3-3_fv0STkwEo6P8MdaFwripy5/">http://noticias.lainformacion.com/arte-cultura-y-espectaculos/videojuegos/la-tumba-de-atari-en-busca-del-tesoro-enterrado-3-3_fv0STkwEo6P8MdaFwripy5/</a></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The article seems to take excerpts from the following quotes:</p>

<blockquote><p>We didn&#8217;t get too far into specifics before the reality of the costs of the project set in. (Gas prices rose drastically in the US during 2008, and we didn&#8217;t have a very efficient vehicle.) However, I did schedule an interview with the mayor of Alamogordo, New Mexico (which we canceled, obviously), and we uncovered news articles from around that time.</p>

<p>The most important thing I realized is that the story may in fact just be a myth! There&#8217;s certainly a lot of evidence that it happened, but there&#8217;s also certainly not a fenced in pile of dirt with an &#8220;Atari&#8221; sign hanging on the side anywhere.</p>

<p>Apparently that location is now a parking lot. I don&#8217;t think the owners would have appreciated us trying to dig&#8230; but yeah, we&#8217;d probably find some dirt there and try anyway. It would have been a great scene at least.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Randomly selecting a line of input with uniform distribution without knowing how many lines to expect]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/01/29/randomly-selecting-an-element-from-a-list-with-uniform-distribution-without-using-the-length-of-the-list/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-29T10:44:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/01/29/randomly-selecting-an-element-from-a-list-with-uniform-distribution-without-using-the-length-of-the-list</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Man that title is a mouthful. The concept is simple, but putting it to words takes a bit of work (I think - let me know if you can put it more succinctly!).</p>

<p>The idea is lifted wholesale from this <a href="http://www.reddit.com/tb/17fnb2">/r/math post</a>, which is a cool concept (albiet poorly written). I&#8217;ve tried to make it a little more digestable in <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/math/comments/17fnb2/an_algorithm_to_randomly_select_an_item_from_a/c85bifv">this comment</a> (careful, spoilers!), which I&#8217;ve copied below (without spoilers).</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote><p>You are the head of a casting agency, and need to select an actor for an upcoming commercial. A line of auditioners are outside your office, and you&#8217;ve decided that you do not care which person is chosen. You&#8217;re a fair person, so you would like a method to randomly choose an actor such that each actor has equal probability of being chosen. However, since your office doesn&#8217;t have windows, you&#8217;re only able to see the person at the front of the line (so you cannot tell the length of the line). In addition, your office only fits two people including yourself, and once someone leaves the line or your office they won&#8217;t return. Can you find a method that works?</p></blockquote>

<p>Since I started sitting in on an Advanced Programming course here at Auburn, I&#8217;ve gotten into these programming puzzles, particularly where the solution is at the intersection of programming and mathematics. That&#8217;s essentially what this is after all:</p>

<ul>
<li>You expect a stream of input (let&#8217;s say unique strings split into lines, and no more than 10000 of them).</li>
<li>You only have enough memory to store one line of input at a time, and an integer. (Why? Because.)</li>
<li>You want to print a <em>random</em> line out of the input, with uniform distribution. That is, the first line of input has the same probability of being printed as the last line, as the middle line, as the 23rd line, etc.</li>
</ul>


<p>Now, if we were able to store the whole stream of input, there&#8217;s no problem. Quick python solution:</p>

<pre><code>foo = ['a', 'b', 'c', 'd', 'e'] # captured earlier from input
import random
print random.choice(foo)
</code></pre>

<p>Maybe that&#8217;s a case of <a href="http://xkcd.com/353/">import antigravity</a>, but solutions in any other languages should be similarly simple.</p>

<p>However, the above solution requires storing the entire stream of input, and we are forbidden from doing so. Basically, as we&#8217;re fed each line, we have to either store it (and remove all knowledge of any previously stored line), or ignore it forever. How could we possibly know whether we&#8217;re going to choose the 1st guy, or the 2nd guy, or the nth guy, without seeing them all?</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a great puzzle. See if you can figure it out. The solution is below.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/pImDAzc.jpg" title="This space intentionally left blank." ></p>

<p>The hint (or maybe red herring?) above was this sentence: &#8220;How could we possibly know whether we&#8217;re going to choose the 1st guy, or the 2nd guy, or the nth guy, without seeing them all?&#8221; Because you can&#8217;t, obviously. You require that you choose a particular line with probability 1/len(foo). So you need to know the length of foo before you finally make your decision.</p>

<p>But since you can&#8217;t go back to previous strings in the input, you gotta get creative. And here&#8217;s where the math comes in. Here&#8217;s my solution:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4667906.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># only variables I'm allowed to store/modify
i = 0
stored_string = &quot;No input given!&quot;

# we'll need to be able to make random choices
import random

# solution
while True:
  try:
    i += 1 # count the place of this string/person in line
    if 1 == random.randint(1,i): 
      # make a decision to keep it with probability 1/i
      # note for first person, i=1, so this passes
      stored_string = raw_input()
    else: 
      # otherwise ignore it
      raw_input()
  except EOFError: # ran out of people in line, we're done
    break

# Claim: the line stored had equal probability of being chosen with any other line
print &quot;Result:\n%s&quot; % stored_string </code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>Try it out - it <em>looks</em> like it works. But why? I should prove it.</p>

<p>The proof is simple - let&#8217;s assume the length of the input is $n$ lines, and we should show the probability of printing the $i^{th}$ line is $\frac{1}{n}$. Then&#8230;</p>

<blockquote><p>P(printing $i$) = P(storing $i$) x P(not storing $i+1$) x &#8230; x P(not storing $n$)</p></blockquote>

<p>Mathematically, this translates to:</p>

<p>$$ P(\text{printing }i) = \frac{1}{i} \times \left(1-\frac{1}{i+1}\right) \times \dots \left(1-\frac{1}{n}\right) $$</p>

<p>$$ = \frac{1}{i} \times \frac{i}{i+1} \times \dots \times \frac{n-1}{n} = \frac{1}{n}$$</p>

<p>So cool.</p>

<p>-SXC</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing my Macbook Pro - replacing hard drive SATA cable]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/01/28/fixing-my-macbook-pro/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-28T16:12:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2013/01/28/fixing-my-macbook-pro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, about two weeks ago <a href="https://www.facebook.com/steven.clontz/posts/10101144733985781">I found myself without a working hard drive</a> on my Macbook Pro (13&#8221;, mid-2008). That&#8217;s what I thought anyway <a href="https://www.facebook.com/steven.clontz/posts/10101146355955341">until the hard drive turned out to work fine in an external enclosure</a>.</p>

<p>As it turned out, the fix was simple - replace the SATA cable connecting the hard drive to the logic board. But figuring out that was the problem/solution was a little frustrating, so I wanted to outline what happened here so that someone else may trip across this one day and find it helpful.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The symptoms were simple: I opened my computer out of sleep one Saturday only to discover that while the computer was up and running, it was stuck trying to load something that it never could. This resulted in a pretty spinning rainbow-colored circle that I could move around my screen, but not much else. As it turned out, the OS was trying to access the hard drive, but the cable connecting it to my logic board had given up the ghost.</p>

<p>Upon restarting the computer, the Apple logo appeared on the gray screen, along with the spinning gray wheel like it was trying to load the OS, but five minutes resulted in nothing.</p>

<p>Booting from the Snow Leopard install DVD let me access the Disk Utility. I attempted to unmount the hard drive, but was informed that I could not due to either an &#8220;input/output&#8221; error, or &#8220;could not allocate memory&#8221;. This prevented me from wiping the drive, which I felt at the time was a good attempt to solve the problem (having backed up with Time Machine earlier in the week).</p>

<p>I decided to purchase a new hard drive from Best Buy, but after trying both a Seagate and a Western Digital, I realized I was likely barking up the wrong tree. I borrowed a 3.5 inch SATA external enclosure, carefully installed my 2.5 inch SATA drive, and hooked it up to my laptop via USB. Lo and behold, Disk Utility could easily format the disk and reinstall OSX from the Time Machine backup!</p>

<p>I managed to use my computer on &#8220;life support&#8221; by booting from the external enclosure for two weeks. The 3.5 inch enclosure didn&#8217;t properly secure the hard disk and required external power, so I ordered a 2.5 inch enclosure for just a few bucks here: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002JQNXZC/ref=oh_details_o00_s00_i00">http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002JQNXZC/ref=oh_details_o00_s00_i00</a></p>

<p>Meanwhile, seeing as the hard drive seemed to be functioning fine, I banked on the issue being with the SATA cable connecting it to the logic board. (A friend pointed out it may actually have been an issue with the board itself, but I didn&#8217;t want to entertain that ugly possibility.) Coincidentally, there is a shop in Huntsville, AL that let me order just what I needed online: <a href="http://www.powerbookmedic.com/Hard-Drive-Cable-w--IR-Sensor-for-MacBook-Pro-13-Unibody-p-17336.html">http://www.powerbookmedic.com/Hard-Drive-Cable-w&#8211;IR-Sensor-for-MacBook-Pro-13-Unibody-p-17336.html</a></p>

<p>However, when it came in, it was just a few millimeters too short - I had ordered the wrong version of the part! Everything would plug in fine, but there just wasn&#8217;t enough room for play. I should have taken photos at the time, but here&#8217;s how things are supposed to look, taken from instructions on how to remove the battery:</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/l5injMs.jpg"></p>

<p>Now, see that cable just above the left circle? that&#8217;s the cable connecting the hard drive to the logic board. You can see that it lays flat on the optical disc drive. You can probably imagine the trouble if it were just a tad short.</p>

<p>My solution? I was able to make a snip on the cable over a hole where it was intended to be screwed into the casing to be secured. That slight modification allowed me to connect everything. You can see a similar cable below - the holes on either side of the cable were in the way, but if you don&#8217;t mind mutilating your cable, they can be cut off with an ordinary pair of scissors without harming the actual wires inside.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/WM4THZf.jpg"></p>

<p>With the new cable installed, my computer now runs good as new. Although I have to admit I was surprised how nicely the computer ran off of the external USB enclosure as well - just be careful not to remove the USB cable while the computer is running in that case! I managed to accidentally do that a couple of times, which just locked up the computer until I reset thankfully.</p>

<p>-SXC</p>

<p>ADDENDUM 2013/01/29: A friend just had the same issue! Punchline: she went to the university bookstore, who waived any labor fees and just ordered the cord for $25. Ahhh well, now I know to ask them first next time. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How many distinct outcomes in bowling?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/12/19/how-many-distinct-outcomes-in-bowling/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T22:59:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/12/19/how-many-distinct-outcomes-in-bowling</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I played my final game of bowling in the &#8220;Math Nerd League 2012&#8221;. And maybe my first - I don&#8217;t know if that moniker was in use before today, but it was used to designate the group of my colleagues in the <a href="http://math.auburn.edu/">Auburn University mathematics graduate program</a> who went this afternoon.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m pretty bad at bowling (although since playing a fair bit this year I&#8217;ve improved my average to roughly 80 compared to a dismal 50). So to keep my mind on happier thoughts, I asked the question:</p>

<blockquote>How many different outcomes are there for one game of bowling?</blockquote>




<!-- more -->


<p>Okay, so, let&#8217;s remember how a game of bowling works. There&#8217;s ten frames, and in the first nine frames you get up to two rolls to knock down ten pins. If the first roll knocks down all ten pins, it&#8217;s a &#8220;strike&#8221; and there isn&#8217;t a second roll. We&#8217;re going to ignore which specific pins are knocked down, including whether the frame is &#8220;split&#8221; or not, and only consider how many pins are knocked down on each roll, i.e., what&#8217;s important for scoring.</p>

<p><small>(A split is normally marked on the score when, after the first roll, the remaining pins don&#8217;t include the front pin, and are split into two or more nonadjacent groups. It doesn&#8217;t affect the point total for the game though.)</small></p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/E6xqD.jpg" title="'Results from bowling with some friends back in 2006; 58 was a good score for me at the time.'" ></p>

<p>So, on these first nine frames, the ball is rolled down the lane, and zero to ten pins are knocked down. Let&#8217;s say the first roll hits $n$ pins. That means there are $10-n$ pins remaining, and we could hit any number of those (including 0), yielding $11-n$ possibilities. Adding them all up, we get
$$\sum_{n=0} ^ {10} (11-n) = \sum_{n=1} ^ {11} n = 66$$
possibilities per frame.</p>

<p>The final frame is more difficult. The rules change so that if the pins are all knocked down, the bowler gets to roll again, up to three total rolls. It makes sense when you consider how bowling is scored, but we won&#8217;t go into that here.</p>

<p>Ignoring strikes and spares there are $\sum_{n=1} ^ {10} n = 55$ ways to knock down zero to nine pins in two rolls. There are ten ways to get a spare (knocking down all pins in two rolls), and then there are 11 different possibilities for the final roll (hitting zero to ten pins), so this adds $110$ possibilities.</p>

<p>Finally, if there&#8217;s a strike on the first bowl, you have $\sum_{n=2} ^ {11} n=65$ possibilities for the next two rolls besides a strike. And finally, if there&#8217;s a strike, there&#8217;s $11$ possibilities for the final roll. So the final frame has $241$ total possibilities.</p>

<p>So, looking at the entire game, we can figure out the total number of possibilities by multiplying the number of possibilities per frame. So that gives us&#8230; $$66 ^ 9 \cdot 241 \approx 5.73 \cdot 10 ^ {18}$$ possibilities.</p>

<p>Long story short, there&#8217;s a lot of bowling I have left to do before I&#8217;ve seen it all.</p>

<p>-SXC</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guessing passwords]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/12/17/guessing-passwords/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T11:18:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/12/17/guessing-passwords</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s not any deep cryptography going on here, but since I spent 15 minutes answering this person on <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/askmath/comments/14zzhw/i_guessed_the_password_on_my_moms_computer_snot/">/r/askmath</a>, and nobody reads /r/askmath, I&#8217;d take the time to cross-post it here.</p>

<p>The question:</p>

<blockquote>I guessed the password on my Mom&#8217;s computer. &#8220;Snot&#8221;. This isn&#8217;t relevant to anything I can think of in the last 10 years. What are the chances of my guess being correct?</blockquote>




<!-- more -->


<hr />

<p>Depends on the constraints on this password. If you knew it was exactly four lowercase letters (no numbers, no symbols), there are 26<sup>4</sup> = 456,976 possibilities. That makes it a 0.00022% chance.</p>

<p>More realistically, if you knew that the password was a four-letter Scrabble word, there are somewhere around 4,000-5,000 possibilities, so your odds just jumped to 0.02%.</p>

<p>But. If your mother was clever and mixed uppercase and lowercase letters, that increases the number of possibilities by 16 times. (Why? Multiply by two for the first letter being uppercase or lowercase, multiply by two for the second letter, and again, and again. 2*2*2*2=16.) That means we have about 80,000 possibilities, and a 0.00125% chance.</p>

<p>Of course, as soon as you throw out the four-letter constraint, the possibilities explode. But let&#8217;s keep the Scrabble word constraint. According to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Official_Tournament_and_Club_Word_List">Official Tournament and Club Word List article on Wikipedia</a> there are 178,691 Scrabble words, so we&#8217;re back down to 0.00056% for one go, and that&#8217;s assuming all-lowercase.</p>

<p>Finally, just for kicks, let&#8217;s assume all you knew is that the password is somewhere between 1 and 20 characters, and could contain lowercase, uppercase, digits 0-9, or any of the special characters !@#$%^&amp;*(). That&#8217;s 72 possibilities for each character, which Wolfram Alpha informs me gives <a href="http://www.wolframalpha.com/input/?i=%5Csum_%7Bi%3D1%7D%5E%7B20%7D+72%5Ei">14,214,254,150,091,658,100,874,779,924,350,129,800</a> possibilities, with a 0.000000000000000000000000000000000000007% chance of guessing correctly.</p>

<p>tl;dr: you got lucky. But keep in mind that I&#8217;m not surprised that out of the millions of users on Reddit, someone got this lucky. After all, people win the lottery all the time - just not me.</p>

<hr />

<p>-SXC</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LaTeX is turing complete!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/12/15/latex-is-turing-complete/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T09:24:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/12/15/latex-is-turing-complete</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, I knew <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LaTeX">LaTeX</a> was the best mathematical markup out there, but I didn&#8217;t realize it was Turing complete. Here&#8217;s an article that shows how to compute the Fibonacci sequence:</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.scribtex.com/latex-is-turing-complete-51805">http://blog.scribtex.com/latex-is-turing-complete-51805</a></p>

<p>Makes me wonder where I can save myself some time by having LaTeX do certain computations for me in my paper rather than doing them myself? I suppose this would likely negatively affect compile time, however.</p>

<p>-SXC</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using email addresses for Django usernames]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/11/15/using-email-addresses-for-django-usernames/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-15T12:58:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/11/15/using-email-addresses-for-django-usernames</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/">Django</a> is a great Python framework for database-driven sites. It&#8217;s what we use for <a href="http://www.teloga.com">Teloga</a> in fact. But there&#8217;s one thing that bugs me: usernames are case-sensitive.</p>

<p>With Teloga busy serving both the <a href="http://www.teloga.com/networks/aubands/">Auburn University Bands</a> and the <a href="http://www.teloga.com/networks/aba/">Alabama Bandmasters Association</a>, it didn&#8217;t take too long for us to realize that this is very unintuitive for users. We received weekly emails complaining that this person couldn&#8217;t log into their account, and invariably it&#8217;d be caused by the usage of <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#111;&#x3a;&#83;&#x74;&#x65;&#x76;&#101;&#x6e;&#x40;&#x54;&#x65;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#103;&#97;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;">&#83;&#x74;&#x65;&#x76;&#x65;&#x6e;&#64;&#84;&#101;&#108;&#x6f;&#103;&#97;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;</a> instead of <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#x74;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#115;&#x74;&#x65;&#118;&#101;&#110;&#64;&#116;&#x65;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#103;&#97;&#46;&#99;&#x6f;&#109;&#46;">&#x73;&#116;&#101;&#118;&#x65;&#110;&#64;&#116;&#101;&#108;&#x6f;&#x67;&#x61;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;&#46;</a> That had to go.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First things first. Before the case-sensitivity even came up, we first decided we wanted to use emails as logins. In addition, we&#8217;re going to need longer usernames than the 30 characters Django allows out of the box, since email addresses can <a href="http://email.about.com/od/emailbehindthescenes/f/address_length.htm">be up to 256 characters long</a>.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s where <a href="https://github.com/GoodCloud/django-longer-username">django-longer-username</a> comes in. It&#8217;s a really nice plugin which provides a <a href="http://south.aeracode.org/">South</a> migration for your database and tweaks all the admin forms appropriately.</p>

<p>Once we have a setup for longer usernames (we went with 75 characters as sufficient for our needs), we needed to create our own registration form. <a href="http://www.jdabbs.com">James</a> took care of this for Teloga. Here&#8217;s a sketch of what ours looks like:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
<span class='line-number'>33</span>
<span class='line-number'>34</span>
<span class='line-number'>35</span>
<span class='line-number'>36</span>
<span class='line-number'>37</span>
<span class='line-number'>38</span>
<span class='line-number'>39</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>class RegistrationForm(forms.Form):
</span><span class='line'>    email = forms.EmailField(
</span><span class='line'>        max_length=75,  # must be 30 without longerusername
</span><span class='line'>        widget=forms.TextInput(attrs={'class': 'xlarge'}),
</span><span class='line'>        label='Email')
</span><span class='line'>    password = forms.CharField(
</span><span class='line'>        widget=forms.PasswordInput(attrs={'class': 'xlarge'}),
</span><span class='line'>        label='Password')
</span><span class='line'>    password_confirmation = forms.CharField(
</span><span class='line'>        widget=forms.PasswordInput(attrs={'class': 'xlarge'}),
</span><span class='line'>        help_text='Enter the same password as above, for verification.',
</span><span class='line'>        label='Confirm password'
</span><span class='line'>    )
</span><span class='line'>    
</span><span class='line'>    def clean_email(self):
</span><span class='line'>        """ Verifies that this email is not already in use """
</span><span class='line'>        email = self.cleaned_data['email'].lower() # Oh hey, this is important.
</span><span class='line'>        try:
</span><span class='line'>            User.objects.get(email=email)
</span><span class='line'>            raise forms.ValidationError('That email address is already associated with an account.')
</span><span class='line'>        except User.DoesNotExist:
</span><span class='line'>            return email
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    def clean_password_confirmation(self):
</span><span class='line'>        """ Verifies that both password fields match """
</span><span class='line'>        data = self.cleaned_data
</span><span class='line'>        pswd = data.get('password', '')
</span><span class='line'>        conf = data.get('password_confirmation', '')
</span><span class='line'>        if pswd and (pswd != conf):
</span><span class='line'>            raise forms.ValidationError("The password confirmation didn't match.")
</span><span class='line'>        return conf
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    def register(self):
</span><span class='line'>        """ Creates a new user object. """
</span><span class='line'>        data = self.cleaned_data
</span><span class='line'>        email = data['email']  # We will use the email address as both u.username and u.email
</span><span class='line'>        password = data['password']
</span><span class='line'>        user = User.objects.create_user(email, email=email, password=password)
</span><span class='line'>        return user</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I&#8217;ll draw attention to this line:</p>

<pre><code>email = self.cleaned_data['email'].lower() # Oh hey, this is important.
</code></pre>

<p>This is getting back to the point I made at first: case sensitivity for usernames sucks. Particularly when you&#8217;re dealing with emails: while it&#8217;s up to each email provider to decide if they want their email addresses to be case-sensitive, most of them make the (smart) decision to ignore capitalization. So do yourself a favor and ignore it yourself. (In our case, we didn&#8217;t at first, and had a few dozen users make duplicate accounts with various capitalizations of their email address.)</p>

<p>Now, using this form you will have users with all-lowercase email addresses set as the username. So now it&#8217;s time to get them logged in.</p>

<p>We&#8217;re actually just going to do a short adjustment to the stock AuthenticationForm. We need to make sure that the length of the username field is increased to 75, and we better make sure we clean up the username/email so that it&#8217;s all lowercase. (Otherwise you&#8217;re going to get a rightfully perturbed user complaining that they registered with <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#x53;&#116;&#101;&#118;&#101;&#110;&#64;&#84;&#x65;&#108;&#x6f;&#x67;&#x61;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x6d;">&#83;&#116;&#x65;&#118;&#101;&#110;&#x40;&#84;&#101;&#108;&#x6f;&#x67;&#97;&#x2e;&#99;&#x6f;&#109;</a> but they cannot log in, because you stored their email as <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#105;&#x6c;&#116;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#x73;&#x74;&#101;&#x76;&#101;&#x6e;&#x40;&#x74;&#x65;&#108;&#x6f;&#x67;&#97;&#46;&#x63;&#111;&#109;&#x2e;">&#x73;&#x74;&#101;&#118;&#101;&#110;&#x40;&#x74;&#x65;&#108;&#x6f;&#103;&#x61;&#x2e;&#x63;&#111;&#109;&#46;</a>)</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>from django.contrib.auth.forms import AuthenticationForm as StockAuthenticationForm
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>class AuthenticationForm(StockAuthenticationForm):
</span><span class='line'>    username = forms.EmailField(max_length=75, label='Email')  # requires longerusername
</span><span class='line'>    # don't forget to make the email lowercase
</span><span class='line'>    def clean_username(self):
</span><span class='line'>        u = self.cleaned_data.get('username')
</span><span class='line'>        return u.lower()</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>So, all in all there isn&#8217;t anything too fancy here, but I was surprised I couldn&#8217;t find a walkthrough online so I thought I could whip one up. Let me know if you have any comments!</p>

<p>-SXC</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[9 Hours, 9 Persons, 9 Doors]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/11/05/9-hours-9-persons-9-doors/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-05T13:33:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/11/05/9-hours-9-persons-9-doors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having spent a lot of my weekend playing it (after representing Teloga at the <a href="http://teloga.com/networks/aubands/alumni-band/fall-2012/">26th Annual Auburn Alumni Band Reunion</a>), I wanted to make a quick, mostly spoiler-free post about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/999:_Nine_Hours,_Nine_Persons,_Nine_Doors"><em>999: 9 Hours, 9 Persons, 9 Doors</em></a> (2010). It&#8217;s a visual novel / room escape / puzzle / adventure game for the Nintendo DS.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/8xVM5.jpg"></p>

<p>While I was mostly a Nintendo kid, I have fond memories of playing Sierra&#8217;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Torin's_Passage">Torin&#8217;s Passage</a> on the PC, which jump-started my interest in story-driven and combatless games. These games are also probably a big influence in my taste in <a href="http://auburnpuzzleparty.wikia.com/wiki/APP5">story-driven puzzle parties</a> as well.</p>

<p>The concept of <em>999</em> is simple: big scary guy (&#8220;Zero&#8221;) in a gas mask kidnaps you and eight other people, forces you to play a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saw_(film)">game</a>, and slaps a wristwatch on you that will kill if you break the rules rather than solve his puzzles. But the best part of the game is tough to explain without spoilers. I&#8217;ll just say: it has the best setup for alternate endings of any game I&#8217;ve played.</p>

<p>By the way, I was very impressed that the game doesn&#8217;t shy away (too) much from using math. There&#8217;s a bit of modular arithmetic involved in the game: each player has a number on their bracelet, and several doors are also marked with numbers. In order for a group to pass through a numbered door, the &#8220;digital root&#8221; of the bracelets (more commonly known as the sum of the numbers modulo nine) must match that number. This makes a major part of the story a mathematical whodunit once the group splits up early on and it&#8217;s discovered that some subset of them opened a door secretly (to a particular end which I&#8217;ll keep secret for this post).</p>

<p>I do wish the characters would have caught onto some of the slicker tricks to computing digital roots. For example, the players 1 through 9 have a digital root of 9. But if players 1 and 2 are sitting out for some reason, the group&#8217;s digital root is now 6. That means for all players to progress simultaneously, they must split up and pass through doors whose digital root is also 6. The characters make most of their conclusions through exhaustive search, but when I was faced with doors 3, 7, and 8, I quickly realized that 7 &amp; 8 (=15=6) were the only real choices. (Well, unless you wanted to leave some players behind, but who would do that?&#8230;) And the only trick then was finding a group to sum to 7 (or 16 or 25), since the other group necessarily had to sum to 8 (or 17 or 26 or etc etc).</p>

<p>Incidentally, while I keep talking about modular arithmetic, the game didn&#8217;t present it that way. Instead, they used the divisibility trick for nine to describe how to calculate a digital root: add the digits of the sum, repeat until only one digit remains. All in all, it&#8217;s a fun metapuzzle for the game. (And not bad fodder for the <a href="http://auburnpuzzleparty.wikia.com/wiki/A.M.P.%27d_Challenge">AMP&#8217;d Challenge</a> either&#8230; maybe I should flesh out an idea based on this.)</p>

<p>But about those endings. There&#8217;s a lot of discussion out there about the optimal way to play through the game. There are six (well, five and a half) endings that the game gives you credit for, and it&#8217;s tough to find them all without a little direction (which I attempted when I first played through the game two years ago). So if I may do so, and I promise not to reveal any spoilers, here are my two suggested ways to play through <em>999</em> if you have the chance to pick it up.</p>

<h3>What you should know</h3>

<p>In this game you will make three choices between which door you&#8217;d like to enter. If you get a &#8220;bad end&#8221;, which one you get is pretty much just determined on your third choice. The game intends for you to play through it multiple times and stumble upon one of the three ends which, well, aren&#8217;t so bad.</p>

<p>However, by paying attention to what interests the other characters, and figuring out which doors you need to go through to progress certain story arcs, you can arrive at one of the three more interesting ends. Realizing this might be enough for you to deduce how to proceed.</p>

<h3>The quickest way</h3>

<p>You should approach <em>999</em> more like you&#8217;re going to read a book than play a game, which means you&#8217;ll be spending a lot of time reading. And on the replays, you&#8217;ll be spending a lot of time holding Right on the D-pad to fast-forward through text you&#8217;ve already seen.</p>

<p>So that&#8217;s why I don&#8217;t blame you if you want to get through things as quickly as possible. Here are directions for seeing every puzzle and ending using minimal playthroughs:</p>

<p class="spoiler">1st. Choose the following doors: 4, 8, 1</p>




<p class="spoiler">2nd. Choose the following doors: 4, 7, 6</p>




<p class="spoiler">3rd. Choose the following doors: 5, 3, 2</p>




<p class="spoiler">4th. Choose the following doors: 5, 8, 6</p>


<p>At this point, you may want to try and solve the puzzle of which path to take for your final ending. Pay close attention to a hint given at the end of the last ending.</p>

<p class="spoiler">Last. Choose the following doors: 4, 7, 1. This unlocks the final two endings (one of which is where the game cuts off this ending early if you haven&#8217;t done the 5, 8, 6 ending). Also, you need to be sure to learn everything you can from the other characters, and help them out where you can, or certain story checks will fail and you&#8217;ll get the same ending as choosing 4, 8, 1.</p>


<h3>A little bit longer</h3>

<p>This is a streamlined version how I ended up playing my first time with the game. There&#8217;s more backtracking, but you get to actually experience that &#8220;half&#8221; ending I keep talking about.</p>

<p class="spoiler">1st. Choose the following doors: 4, 8, 6</p>




<p class="spoiler">2nd. Choose the following doors: 5, 3, 2</p>




<p class="spoiler">3rd. Choose the following doors: 4, 7, 1. However, refuse to listen to optional plot points and don&#8217;t help the other characters when possible.</p>




<p class="spoiler">4th. Choose the following doors again: 4, 7, 1. This time, listen to everything and help a certain person out.</p>


<p>At this point, you may want to try and solve the puzzle of which path to take for your next ending. Pay close attention to a hint given at the end of the last ending.</p>

<p class="spoiler">5th. Choose the following doors: 5, 8, 6</p>




<p class="spoiler">Last. Choose the following doors a final time: 4, 7, 1. Again, listen to everything and help a certain person out. Enjoy the epiphany.</p>


<h3>And every other combination</h3>

<p>I ran across this image on Reddit, which maps out all the possible paths and endings. Pretty cool to look over once you&#8217;ve seen them all yourself: <a href="http://i.imgur.com/amjI5.gif">http://i.imgur.com/amjI5.gif</a></p>

<p>That&#8217;s all I&#8217;ve got. If you&#8217;ve gotten this far then I assume you&#8217;ve played the game or plan to. But if not, and you think you&#8217;d enjoy this psychological thriller, then I encourage you to give it a try! (Also, the sequel came out&#8230; maybe I&#8217;ll have time to play it one day, heh.)</p>

<p>-SXC</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marked-down resume]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/10/28/resume-now-online/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-28T23:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/10/28/resume-now-online</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A project that had been almost as long overdue as reviving <a href="http://www.stevenclontz.com">http://www.stevenclontz.com</a> was updating my neglected resume.</p>

<p>The tl;dr version: check it out at <a href="http://resume.stevenclontz.com">http://resume.stevenclontz.com</a>! But if you think that looks nice and would like to check out the web app that powers it, please read on. :-)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I knew I wanted my resume to be web-first. The last time I wrote a resume (back in early 2011) I had TeX&#8217;d it up locally. And hey, at least that&#8217;s better than a Word document, right? However, and maybe I&#8217;ve gotten lazier in the past two years&#8230; but trudging through this didn&#8217;t seem appealing:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>\begin{ressection}{Education}
</span><span class='line'>    \begin{ressubsec}{Auburn University}{Auburn, AL}{Bachelor's of Science and Master of Science in Mathematics}
</span><span class='line'>        \ressubitem{Undergraduate GPA: 3.88 (overall), 4.00 (Major)}
</span><span class='line'>        \ressubitem{Undergraduate Graduation Date: May, 2008 (Summa Cum Laude, University Honors Scholar)}
</span><span class='line'>        \ressubitem{Masters GPA: 4.00}
</span><span class='line'>        \ressubitem{Masters Graduation Date: December, 2010}
</span><span class='line'>        \ressubitem{Currently pursuing Doctor of Philosophy in Mathematics at Auburn}
</span><span class='line'>    \end{ressubsec}
</span><span class='line'>\end{ressection}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>So began my search for a simpler way. My first instinct was <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a> - it&#8217;s what <a href="http://www.teloga.com">Teloga</a> uses, it&#8217;s what <a href="http://www.reddit.com">Reddit</a> uses, heck, it&#8217;s what this blog uses. And certainly this markup is a lot friendlier to read and edit:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>##Education
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>####Auburn University - Auburn, AL
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>* Bachelor's of Science in Mathematics (2008)
</span><span class='line'>    * 3.9 overall GPA | 4.0 major GPA
</span><span class='line'>    * Summa Cum Laude | University Honors Scholar | Phi Kappa Phi | Phi Beta Kappa 
</span><span class='line'>    * Honors thesis in unfoldings of convex polyhedra | Undergraduate Research Fellow
</span><span class='line'>* Master of Science in Mathematics (2010)
</span><span class='line'>    * 4.0 GPA
</span><span class='line'>    * Master thesis in linearly ordered topological spaces
</span><span class='line'>* Doctoral Candidate in Mathematics
</span><span class='line'>    * Currently writing dissertation on limited information strategies in topological games</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>So I thought the simple thing to do would be to just make a page on this blog for the resume. And when I did, it didn&#8217;t look half bad either.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/U6xQ4.png"></p>

<p>The only problem&#8230; I&#8217;d probably need a PDF version as well, and maybe even have to print it at some point. Silly old media.</p>

<p>Now, keeping multiple copies of the same resume definitely violates <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don't_repeat_yourself">DRY</a>; I wanted a slicker solution. So my first idea was to just print the webpage from Chrome and save it as a PDF.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/kdRdF.png"></p>

<p>Yikes.</p>

<p>So, the issue that Octopress&#8217;s default theme doesn&#8217;t have a nice print stylesheet is a topic for another day, but I figured there was someone else out there of a similar mind that would have already paved the way for a nice way to share a resume written in Markdown.</p>

<p>As it often does, the Google helped me find an answer earlier today: <a href="http://pseudoweb.net/2010/10/25/developing-your-resume/">http://pseudoweb.net/2010/10/25/developing-your-resume/</a></p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/nAmTh.png"></p>

<p>Looks nice, and it prints well too. Incidentally, Mr. Welch&#8217;s resume app makes use of this very cool Ruby gem called <a href="http://www.sinatrarb.com/">Sinatra</a> which I may need to look more into for simple apps. I&#8217;m new to Ruby (hey maybe I can add it to my resume now though) but hacking his app to do what I wanted was pretty straight forward.</p>

<p>I added a few extra variables to the configuration YAML to store the URL of the page itself and the URL of a QR Code image leading to that URL, which I use in a couple of nice extra features:</p>

<ol>
<li>If the page is printed, it adds a line to the top: &#8220;Optimized for web | <a href="http://resume_url">http://resume_url</a>&#8221;</li>
<li>A QR code floats in the upper right of the page, also linking to the digital version of the resume.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2WrpD.png"></p>

<p>You can see it in action at <a href="http://resume.stevenclontz.com">my resume page</a>, and my forked version of the app can be found <a href="https://github.com/StevenClontz/Resume">on my Github</a>.</p>

<p>There are still a couple of tweaks that might be nice to have if I decide to work on this more later.</p>

<ul>
<li>It&#8217;d be preferable to have a script to burn a PDF from the resume.md Markdown file rather than using a browser printout, possibly leveraging LaTeX.</li>
<li>A simple change would be to move some of the basic data (name, address, etc.) into the configuration file to standardize the header.</li>
</ul>


<p>In the meantime, I hope you found all this interesting, and maybe I&#8217;ve inspired you to use revision control and Markdown to maintain your own resume!</p>

<p>-SXC</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auburn Puzzle Party 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/10/28/auburn-puzzle-party-5/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-28T23:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/10/28/auburn-puzzle-party-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In case you hadn&#8217;t heard me talk about it yet, <a href="http://auburnpuzzleparty.wikia.com/wiki/APP5_Wrap-Up">here&#8217;s my wrap-up of Auburn Puzzle Party 5</a> on the Auburn Puzzle Party wiki.</p>

<p>And if you haven&#8217;t checked out the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLooILs0YfKkEWPeFpZdDis2GuQ2aP-weO">APP5 videos, including the Puzzle Rock Anthem</a> yet, you&#8217;re missing out. See if you can solve the &#8220;hidden&#8221; puzzle in the videos too.</p>

<p>-SXC</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New blog powered by Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/10/25/new-blog-powered-by-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-25T08:40:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/10/25/new-blog-powered-by-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! Thanks for checking out my new blog*. After deciding I didn&#8217;t need to waste so much cash on domain names I don&#8217;t use and web space I barely needed, I took down stevenclontz.com along with most of my other old PHP/Wordpress sites. I&#8217;ll get stevenclontz.com to point here sometime soon.</p>

<p>Thanks to <a href="http://jdabbs.com">James Dabbs</a> for showing <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> to me the other day - a blogging system with <a href="http://git-scm.com/">Git</a> revision control and hosting by <a href="http://heroku.com">Heroku</a> sounds alright to me.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll be working on my <a href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/about/">About</a> page and getting my <a href="http://resume.stevenclontz.com">Resume</a> up to date over the coming days.  Email me at <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#x6c;&#116;&#x6f;&#58;&#x73;&#116;&#101;&#118;&#x65;&#x6e;&#46;&#x63;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#x6e;&#116;&#x7a;&#64;&#103;&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#46;&#99;&#x6f;&#109;">&#x73;&#116;&#101;&#x76;&#101;&#110;&#x2e;&#99;&#108;&#x6f;&#110;&#116;&#x7a;&#x40;&#x67;&#109;&#97;&#105;&#x6c;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x6d;</a> if you need to get in touch with me! See ya.</p>

<p>-SXC</p>

<p><small>*Is this sentence obligatory for a first blog post? I almost always see it, and it sounded awkward not to include it. Thanks again I guess. :-)</small></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello world]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/10/24/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T14:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenclontz.com/blog/2012/10/24/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am learning about Octopress here. Hiya everyone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
